Male, 27 | Bengaluru +91 90301 31517 | tmidhunr@gmail.com

MIDHUN THADURU

SUMMARY

Data science professional with 5.5 years of experience in analytics, specializing in statistical analysis, exploratory data analysis, data mining and machine learning using open source tools for analysis. Interested in Data Mining, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Ather Energy Pvt. Ltd.

Data Analyst - Vehicle Intelligence

Bengaluru, Karnataka January 2016 - Present

Role and Responsibilities: Explore and understand engineering sub-systems of an electric scooter. Build smart features for scooter, develop tools and support internal stake holders with data analysis, help them take better decisions and build smart scooter.

Diagnostics

■ Health Metrics – Built metrics to evaluate performance and health of scooters. Incorporated a pipeline to calculate and send the results scooter back-end database for retrieval and analysis. SQL, Python

Algorithms & Smart Features

■ Trip Identification and Trip History - Developed an algorithm based on the data from the vehicle to identify riding sessions. Built application to calculate trip metrics for Ather mobile app. Created an automated pipeline for deploying the application on AWS Elastic Beanstalk using Gitlab CI/CD. SQL, Python

Product Insights

- Rider Survey Analysis Analyzed the typical rider behavior and the vehicle usage for product optimization. Helped product team in improving the scooter specifications. R
- Open Rate Analysis Analyzed and used tree based methods to identify the pattern in the decline of reading newsletters.
 Helped the marketing team improve the newsletter open rate from 24 to 43%. R, postgreSQL

Experimentation

 Dashboard Design Testing - Provided a comprehensive analysis for scooter dashboard UI. Performed sentiment analysis based on the reactions from the respondents. R

Data Pipeline & Tools

- Make Every Scooter Smart and Intelligent Built data pipeline from DAQ for ICE scooters. Built an automated dashboard on GCP for validating, analyzing the ride data. R, Shiny
- Supported enginnering teams for ad-hoc analysis and built internal tools to automate their analysis. R, Shiny, Grafana
- Contributed to the internal libraries. R, Python

Graymatter Software Services Pvt. Ltd.

Associate Data Analyst - Insurance Domain

Bengaluru, Karnataka March 2015 — December 2015

Role and Responsibilities: Explore insurance domain. Build and test hypothesis and develop models using statistical methods and machine learning algorithms and deploy the models into the product.

Projects:

- Customer Segmentation and Cross Selling Clustered customers based on their explicit and implicit behavior to cross sell
 insurance products. Worked on customer market segmentation using k-means & Partitioning Around Medoids clustering
 algorithms. R, SQL
- Motor Insurance Fraud Claim Detection Built fraud detection model based on the customer vehicle profile, behavior profile and demographic behavior using Logistic Regression. Improved the model accuracy using tree based methods. R, SQL
- Designed product for Cross-sell and Up-sell which includes data extraction, selection, rule engine recommendation and model based recommendation, monitoring and recalibrating the models. R

Associate Cosultant

Project:

• Price Comparison of Crude Oil vs retail market in India - Analyzed drop in crude oil prices in comparison with Indian retail market and the effect of deregulation of fuel prices in India. Collected the data by web-scraping using python beautiful soup. R

HACKATHONS & PROJECTS

- MakeMyTrip Data Science Hiring Challenge, Classification Problem Worked on 1 week online hackathon on HackerEarth. Ranked 6th of more than 3500 participants. R
- Go-Jek Data Science Hackathon, Driver Duration Online Prediction Built regression model based on driver ping timestamps and driver details. R
- McKinsey Healthcare Analytics Hackathon, Prediction of Probability of Stroke to Patients Worked on 24 hour online hackathon challenge on Analytics Vidhya. Used Logistic Regression to predict probability of stroke. Ranked 59th of more than 2000 participants. R

PUBLICATIONS AND RECOGNITION

CSI Communications

Visualization - Techniques, Methods and Tools

Authored an article on the importance of visualization, steps involved in the process of visualization, available graphical techniques, popular methods in data visualization and available open source data visualization tools.

EDUCATION

Birla Institute of Technoloy and Sciences

Bachelors of pharmacy(Honors)

Pilani, Rajasthan Class of 2013

Cover Story

November, 2014

Important Courses & Electives: Mathematics, Probability and Statistics, Computer Programming, Object Oriented Programming, Optimization, Operations Research, Principles of Economics, Principles of Management

Jawahar Navodaya Vidyalaya

A.I.S.S.C.E (M.P.C, Computer Science)

Warangal, A.P Class of 2008

Achieved second in Math Olympiad Test at school level and Selected for Regional Math Olympiad Test, 2006

POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

Gandhi Bhawan - BITS, Pilani

Sports Secretary

Pilani, Rajasthan August 2010 — May 2011

Elected as Hostel Sports Secretary through elections (220+ members);

- Managed sports inventory within allotted budget and conducted intra-bhawan sports competition
- Won Intra-BITS overall championship for the year 2011

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Tools & Languages R, SQL, Python, Google Cloud Platform, Grafana, Git, Linux, AWS Elastic Beanstalk

Techniques Regression, Classification, Decision Trees, Clustering

Skills Statistics, Machine Learning, Web Scraping, Regular Expressions

Hobbies Fantasy Premier League, Reading Novels, Trekking

Sports and Games Football, Table Tennis, Badminton, Cricket

page 2 of 2